## Emanuele Stoppa Curriculum Vitea

- Email emanuele@ematipico.xyz
- LinkedIn <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/emanuelestoppa">https://www.linkedin.com/in/emanuelestoppa</a>
- BlueSky <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/ematipico.xyz">https://bsky.app/profile/ematipico.xyz</a>
- **GitHub** <a href="https://github.com/ematipico">https://github.com/ematipico</a>
- Site: <a href="https://ematipico.xyz">https://ematipico.xyz</a>

## Senior Software Engineer

I am a **Senior software engineer** with 15+ years of experience in the field of web development and tooling. My experience span from frontend development, such as focus in accessibility, work on design systems with automated CI/CD, to tooling for web applications such as CLIs.

### Career History

The Astro Technology Company (February 2022 - Current)

Senior Software Engineer

Core maintainer of the open source project <u>Astro</u>. Worked on various parts of the project such as the middleware system, the internalization, refactored the internal build pipeline, edge middleware for Netlify and Vercel adapters, <u>CSP</u> and <u>CSRF</u>.

- Tech Stack: TypeScript, Go, GitHub Actions, Node.js
- Employment: full-time employee, remote

Rome Tools Inc. (June 2021 - December 2022)

Senior Software Engineer

Core maintainer of the open source project <u>Rome Tools</u>, now discontinued. I drove the rewrite of the tool from TypeScript to Rust. Wrote the first implementation of the formatter, wrote the CLI, the analyser and the WebAssembly bindings. Drove the plan to release the first stable release (v10.0.0). Implemented visitors API to deserialize JSON files using the internal parser.

- Tech Stack: Rust, TypeScript, GitHub Actions
- Employment: full-time employee, remote

Wise Emotions (September 2020 - May 2021)

Senior Software Engineer

Migrated various frontend code bases from JavaScript to TypeScript, coached team members in TypeScript. Created an internal design system with automated CI/CD, with publishing of Storybook for designers. Implemented a Node.js service with NestJS: the services uses the webhooks of the CMS, and then it index certain contents with Algolia. The content is divided by locale.

- Tech Stack: React, TypeScript, Node.js, NestJs, Redux Toolkit, Google Cloud
- Employment: contractor, remote

**Bord Gáis Energy** (September 2018 - August 2020)

Senior Software Engineer

Part of the web team, I contributed to different fronts: built the new <u>website of the company</u>, designed and implemented the SSR solution of the website (AWS lambda, terraform), worked on projects to deliver a better experience during the purchase of the products, a new dashboard for business customers.

- Tech Stack: React, TypeScript, Node.js, AWS
- Employment: contractor, hybrid

Bank of America Merrill Lynch (May 2017 - August 2018)

Senior UI Developer

Some achievements are: testing framework (mocha) through Node.js (before non-existent), optimisation of the webpack build, code splitting among the different sub-applications of the main application; migration from gulp; moving all the code from CommonJS to ESM; add Redux as state manager for saving and organising data; React as UI library;

• Tech Stack: React, JavaScript, webpack

• Employment: contractor, on-site

#### Fenergo (October 2016 - April 2017)

Senior UI Developer

Worked on a new client application version, which involved different technologies stack and property concepts. I was hired as ReactJS/Redux expert, JavaScript expert and performance advocate. Worked closely with the team leader to implement new features for developers and end users. I proposed various refactors inside the application to help performance.

• Tech Stack: React, JavaScript, SASS, webpack

• Employment: contractor, on-site

City Wonders LTD (October 2015 - September 2016)

Senior Frontend Developer

• Tech Stack: React, JavaScript, Redux, SASS, Umbraco, .NET

• Employment: full-time employee, on-site

Paddy Power (March 2013 - September 2015)

Web Developer

• Tech Stack: Sencha Touch, Cordova, AngularJS, Grunt, SASS

• Employment: full-time employee, on-site

Nextre Engineering S.r.l. (May 2010 - February 2013)

PHP Developer

• Tech Stack: PHP, jQuery, CodeIgniter, WordPress, Java, Groovy

• Employment: full-time employee, on-site

Scube NewMedia (January 2010 - May 2010)

iOS Developer

• Tech Stack: Objective-C, JSON, Java

• Employment: full-time employee, on-site

#### Education

# Degree in Communication Technology

Università Degli Studi di Milano

September 2006 - December 2009

Università Degli Studi di Brescia

October 2005 - July 2006

High School diploma, IT Technical Institute

September 2000 - June 2005